Register of the Vladimir N. Ipatieff Papers, 1896-1953
Hoover Institution Archives
Vladimir N. Ipatieff Papers
1896-1953
2000C14
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 7 microfilm reels (1.8 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, correspondence, patents, biographical data, and photographs, relating to chemical research in Russia and the Soviet Union, and to Russian émigré affairs.
Ipatieff, Vladimir N. (Vladimir Nikolaevich), 1867-1952.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Biography
Vladimir Nikolaevich Ipatieff was born on 21 November 1867 in Moscow, Russia. His early career was that of a military man: in 1887 he graduated from the Mikhailovskoe artilleriiskoe uchilishche, and in 1892 from the Mikhailovskaia artilleriiskaia akademiia. But his interest in chemistry diverted him from a strictly military path. Teaching the subject at the Artillery Academy, he went on to get a doctorate from St. Petersburg University in 1907, while advancing in military rank to major general in 1910. From 1906 to 1916, he taught chemistry at the University as well, and was made a member of the Imperial Academy of Sciences in 1916. As a lieutenant general during the First World War, he served as Director of the Commission for Preparation of Explosives and Chairman of the Chemical Committee.
Following the revolution, he remained in the Soviet Union, where he founded the High Pressure Institute in 1927. But in 1931, while on a trip abroad, he decided not to return and came to the United States, where he taught at Northwestern University from 1931 to 1935. In 1939 he was elected a member of the National Academy of Sciences. Ipatieff died in Chicago on 29 February 1952. Northwestern University dedicated a laboratory in his honor.
Ipatieff authored hundreds of articles on chemistry in a number of languages, as well as textbooks, such as Kolichestvennyi analiz, which he wrote while still a student (St. Petersburg, 1891); a scientific autobiography, Catalytic Reactions at High Pressures and Temperatures (New York, 1936); and personal memoirs, Zhizn' odnogo khimika (New York, 1945), translated into English as The Life of a Chemist (Stanford, 1946). He also held several hundred patents, marking his most significant contributions to science: the formulation of high-octane gasoline, the "cracking" method now used to refine gas, and other discoveries relating to catalytic reactions (especially under high pressures and temperatures), and the synthesis of petroleum and its distillates.
Chronology
1867 November 21 (N.S.) Born, Moscow
1887 Graduated, Mikhailovskoe artilleriiskoe uchilishche
1892 Graduated, Mikhailovskaia artilleriiskaia akademiia Married Varvara Dmitrievna Ermakova
1902 Professor, Mikhailovskaia artilleriiskaia akademiia
1907 Ph.D., chemistry, Petrograd University
1910 Major-General, Imperial Russian Army
1914 Director of Commission for Preparation of Explosives, Russian army
1916 Member, Russian Academy of Sciences
1927 Founded High Pressure Institute
1930 Left the U.S.S.R.
1931 Professor, Northwestern University
1939 Member, National Academy of Sciences, United States
1952 November 29 Died, Chicago, Illinois
Scope and Content
This collection contains the patents and scientific articles of Vladimir N. Ipatieff for his émigré period, as well as a significant amount of biographical material.
Of particular value are the biographical materials collected by Ipatieff and others describing his life and scientific achievements. These materials include clippings, photographs, correspondence, speeches and writings by and about Ipatieff, and relate also to his public and social activities and accomplishments, especially for the benefit of the émigré community.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials and copyright to them (with some exceptions) are the property of the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Chemistry--Russia.; Chemistry--Soviet Union.; Russia.; Russians--United States.; Soviet Union.; United States.
- Vladimir N. Ipatieff papers in the Hoover Institution (Box 1-2)
- Vladimir N. Ipatieff papers in the Museum of Russian Culture (Reel 1-7)
  - Biographical File, 1932-1953.
    Scope and Contents note
    Personal papers, commemorative addresses, congratulatory letters and telegrams, biographical materials (books and articles about Ipatieff) collected by Ipatieff and others, arranged alphabetically by physical form. See also Oversize file.
    - Addresses honoring Ipatieff (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Articles about or mentioning Ipatieff. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/ The Chemical Bulletin, 1937 December (Folder 2)
    - Books about Ipatieff. Includes Vladimir N. Ipatieff Meeting: Chicago Section, American Chemical Society, November 26, 1937, Vladimir N. Ipatieff: Testimonial in Honor of Three Milestones in His Career, Chicago, 1942, and M. Kostevich, V. N. Ipat'ev, Buenos Aires, 1941 (Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1937-1953 (Folder 4)
    - Congratulatory letters and telegrams on the occasion of Ipatieff's 80th birthday, 1947 (Folder 5)
    - Invitations to banquets and other events in honor of Ipatieff, 1937-1942 (Folder 6)
    - Materials collected by others
      - Haensel, Paul
        - Biographical writings on Ipatieff by Haensel and others (Folder 7)
        - Clippings and other printed matter relating to Ipatieff (Folder 8)
        - Correspondence
          - General, 1940-1943 (Folder 9)
          - Ipatieff, Vladimir Nikolaevich, 1940 (Folder 10)
      - Konstantinov, Petr Filaretovich. Scrapbook of clippings, photographs and writings, including biographical notes on Ipatieff, chronology of his career, bibliography and reviews of his works, correspondence (Folder 11)
    - Membership cards (Folder 12)
    - Memoirs. See SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/ Zhizn' odnogo khimika
    - Scrapbooks
      - "Catalytic Reactions at High Pressures and Temperatures," clippings, correspondence, programs and other printed matter relating to Ipatieff's scientific discoveries, 1933-1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - "Russian Academy of Sciences Expels Vladimir N. Ipatieff," clippings, 1936-1937 (Folder 2)
    - Subject File - Family. Nicolas d'Ipatieff [son], La liane Efiri, Leopoldville, 1932. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/ 15-oi godovshchine oktiabria (Folder 3)
    - War ration cards (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1952
    Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
    - General, 1940-1952 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Bok, Mariia Petrovna, 1949 (Folder 6)
    - Haensel, Paul. See BIOGRAPHICAL FILE/Materials collected by others
    - Leontii, Archbishop, 1948 (Folder 7)
    - Prigodina, Iuliia L'vovna, 1947 (Folder 8)
    - Sack, Alexander N., 1944 (Folder 9)
    - Yadoff, Oleg, 1947 (Folder 10)
  - Speeches And Writings, 1891-1952.
    Speeches, scientific articles, memoirs, arranged chronologically by title. See also Oversize file/Scrapbooks.
    - Kolichestvennyi Analiz, Printed copy, 1891. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - "Ueber die Caronsäure" ["0rtsbestimmungen in der Terpenreihe"], Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1896. (Folder 12)
    - "Ueber die Einwirkung von Bromwasserstoff auf Kohlenwasserstoffe der Reihe CnH2n-2," Journal für praktische Chemie, Negative photostat, 1896. (Folder 13)
    - "Ueber die Constitution und Synthese von Isopren," Journal für praktische Chemie, Negative photostat, 1897. (Folder 14)
    - "Zur Constitution von Isopren," Journal für praktische Chemie, Negative photostat, 1897. (Folder 15)
    - "O nitrozatakh," Zhurnal russkago fiziko-khimicheskago obshchestva, Negative photostat, 1899. (Folder 16)
    - "O reaktsii khloristago nitrozila na organicheskiia soedineniia, soderzhashchiia dvoinuiu sviaz'," Zhurnal russkago fiziko-khimicheskago obshchestva, Negative photostat, 1899. (Folder 17)
    - "Ueber Allenkohlenwasserstoffe," Journal für praktische Chemie, Negative photostat, 1899. (Folder 18)
    - "Ueber die Einwirkung von Natriummalonsäureester auf Dibromide CnH2nBr2," Journal für praktische Chemie, Negative photostat, 1899. (Folder 19)
    - "Eine neue Synthese von Methyiheptenon," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1901. (Folder 20)
    - "O deistvii natriimalonovago efira na tribromidy," Zhurnal russkago fiziko-khimicheskago obshchestva, Negative photostat, 1901. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "Ob izoprenovoi kislotie," Zhurnal russkago fiziko-khimicheskago obshchestva, Negative photostat, 1901. (Folder 2)
    - "Pyrogenetische Contactreactionen organischer Verbindungen," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1901. (Folder 3)
    - "Sintez dimetilpentadekilkarbinola i deistvie na nego broma," Zhurnal russkago fiziko-khimicheskago obshchestva, Negative photostat, 1901. (Folder 4)
    - "Ueber pyrogenetische Reactionen organischer Substanzen," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1901. (Folder 5)
    - "O deistvii natriimalonovago efira na dibromidy CnH2nBr2," Zhurnal russkago fiziko-khimicheskago obshchestva, Negative photostat, 1902. (Folder 6)
    - "Pyrogenetische Contactreactionen organischer Verbindungen. (Dritte Mittheilung)," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1902. (Folder 7)
    - "Pyrogenetische Contactreactionen organischer Verbindungen. (Vierte Mittheilung)," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1903. (Folder 8)
    - "Pyrogenetische Contactreactionen organischer Verbindungen. (Fünfte Mittheilung)," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1903. (Folder 9)
    - "Pyrogenetische Contactreactionen organischer Verbindungen. (Siebente Mittheilung)," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1903. (Folder 10)
    - "Ueber die Anlagerung von Haloïdwasserstoffen an Aethylenkohlenwasserstoffe in essigsaurer Lösung," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1903. (Folder 11)
    - "Zur Frage über die Zersetzung des Äthylalkohols in Gegenwart verschiedener Katalysatoren," Journal für praktische Chemie, Negative photostat, 1903. (Folder 12)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. Katalytische Isomerisation der Butylene," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1907. (Folder 13)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. Reduktionskatalyse," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1907. (Folder 14)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. Reduktionskatalyse in Gegenwart von Metalloxyden," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1907. (Folder 15)
    - "Kataliticheskiia reaktsii pri vysokikh temperaturakh i davleniiakh. Kataliticheskoe razlozhenie kislot," Zhurnal russkago fiziko-khimicheskago obshchestva, Negative photostat, 1908. (Folder 16)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. (XIII. Mitteilung)," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1908. (Folder 17)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. (XIV. Mitteilung)," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1908. (Folder 18)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. (XV. Mitteilung)," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1908. (Folder 19)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. (XVI. Mitteilung)," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1908. (Folder 20)
    - "Reduktion und Oxydation von Nickeloxyden bei gewöhnlichem und bei hohem Druck," Journal für praktische Chemie, Negative photostat, 1908. (Folder 21)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. XVII. Mitteilung," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1909. (Folder 22)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. XIX. Mitteilung," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1909. (Folder 23)
    - "Über das Verdrängen der Metalle aus wäßrigen Lösungen ihrer salze durch Wasserstoff bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1909. (Folder 24)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. XX. [Mitteilung]," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1910. (Folder 25)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. XXI. [Mitteilung]," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Positive photostat, 1910. (Folder 26)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. XXII. Hydrogenisation der Terpene," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1910. (Folder 27)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. XXII. Zersetzung des Hexans und Hexamethylens; Isomerisation des Hexamethylens," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1911. (Folder 28)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. XXIII. [Mitteilung]," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1911. (Folder 29)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. XXIV. [Mitteilung]," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1911. (Folder 30)
    - "Polymerisation der Äthylen-Kohlenwasserstoffe bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1911. (Folder 31)
    - "Über das Verdrängnung der Metalle aus den wäßrigen Lösungen ihrer Salze durch Wasserstoff bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. II.," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1911. (Folder 32)
    - "Über die Verdrängnung der Metalle aus den wäßrigen Lösungen ihrer Salze durch Wasserstoff bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. III.," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1911. (Folder 33)
    - "Zur Frage über die Entstehung der Naphtha," Journal für praktische Chemie, Positive photostat, 1911. (Folder 34)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. XXV.," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1912. (Folder 35)
    - "Über die Verdrängung der Metalle aus den wäßrigen Lösungen ihrer Salze durch Wasserstoff bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. IV.," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1912. (Folder 36)
    - "Über Zusammenwirken der Katalysatoren," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1912. (Folder 37)
    - "K voprosu o vosstanovlenii zhirov pri pomoshchi okislov nikkelia," Zhurnal russkago fiziko-khimicheskago obshchestva, Negative photostat, 1913. (Folder 38)
    - Katalicheskiia reaktsii pri vysokikh temperaturakh i davleniiakh," Zhurnal russkago fiziko-khimicheskago obshchestva, Negative photostat, 1913. (Folder 39)
    - "Katalytische Reaktionen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken. Hydrogenisation der Phenole mit ungesättigter Seitenkette. XXVI," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1913. (Folder 40)
    - "O vytiesnenii uksusnoi kisloty iz rastvorov eia solei ugol'nym angidridom pri vysokom davlenii," Zhurnal russkago fiziko-khimicheskago obshchestva, Negative photostat (incomplete), 1913. (Folder 41)
    - "Polymerisation der Äthylens bei hoher Temperatur und Druck in Gegenwart von Katalysatoren," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1913. (Folder 42)
    - "Über die Verdrängung der Metalle II. Gruppe ungerader Reihen des periodischen Systems durch Wasserstoff aus Salzlösungen bei hoher Temperatur und unter hohem Druck," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1923. (Folder 43)
    - "Iavleniia polimerizatsii pod vliianiem sovmestnogo deistviia glinozema i zheleza pri vysokikh temperaturakh i davleniiakh," Doklady Rossiiskoi akademii nauk, Negative photostat, 1924. (Folder 44)
    - "Polymerisations-Erscheinungen unter der gemeinschaftlichen Einwirkung von Aluminumoxyd und metallischem Eisen bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1925. (Folder 45)
    - "Réaction entre l'alcool méthylique et le phénol à haute température et sous pression," Bulletin de la Société Chimique de France, Negative photostat, 1925. (Folder 46)
    - "Sur la question de l'éther cyclohexylique," Comptes rendus de l'Académie des Sciences, Negative photostat, 1925. (Folder 47)
    - "Action d'une haute température et de la pression sur quelques dérivés de l'acide benzoïque," Bulletin de la Société chimique de France, Negative photostat, 1926. (Folder 48)
    - "Déplacement du platine par l'hydrogène sous haute pression. Communication préliminaire," Bulletin de la Société Chimique de France, Negative photostat, 1926. (Folder 49)
    - "Einwirkung von Wasserstoff und Wasser auf Phosphor bei hoher Temperatur unter Druck," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1926. (Folder 50)
    - "Hydrierung aromatischer Säuren und ihre Salze unter Druck," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1926. (Folder 51)
    - "Hydrierung von Salzen aromatischer Säuren unter Druck," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1926. (Folder 52)
    - "Hydrogénation du triphénylcarbinol et du phénylfluorènecarbinol sous pression," Bulletin de la Société Chimique de France, Negative photostat, 1926. (Folder 53)
    - "Hydrogénation du triphénylcarbinol et du phénylfluorènecarbinol sous pression," Comptes-rendus de l'Académie des Sciences, Negative photostat, 1926. (Folder 54)
    - "Kondensation der Milchsäure zu Methyl-bernsteinsäure unter dem Einfluß der kombinierten Einwirkung von Katalysatoren bei hohen Drucken und Temperaturen," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1926. (Folder 55)
    - "Sur la réduction des combinaisons chromiques par l'hydrogène sous pression et aux températures élevées," Bulletin de la Société Chimique de France, Negative photostat, 1926. (Folder 56)
    - "Sur l'hydrogénation de la xanthone et du xanthène," Comptes-rendus de l'Académie des Sciences, Negative photostat, 1926. (Folder 57)
    - "Über die Hydrolyse von Salzen aromatischer Sulfonsäuren bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1926. (Folder 58)
    - "Über die katalytische Kondensation von Aceton bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken (I. Mitteilung),", Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1926. (Folder 59)
    - "Die Verdrängung von Metallen, Metalloiden und ihren Oxyden aus Lösungen durch Wasserstoff unter Druck," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1926. (Folder 60)
    - "Einfluß der Konzentration der Wasserstoff-Ionen auf die Verdrängung des Kupfers aus Lösungen bei hohen und Temperaturen," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 61)
    - "L'élimination des métaux et de leurs oxydes, des solutions salines par l'hydrogène sous pression," Bulletin de la Société Chimique de France, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 62)
    - "La formation des silicates cristallisés en milieu aqueux sous pressions et à températures élevées," Bulletin de la Société Chimique de France, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 63)
    - "L'hydrogénation de la dibenzalacétone et de la dibenzylacétone," Bulletin de la Société Chimique de France, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 64)
    - "L'hydrogénation de la dibenzalacétone et de la dibenzylacétone," Comptes-rendus de l' Académie des Sciences, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 65)
    - "L'hydrogénation sous pression du tétraphénylméthane et du p-oxytétrphénylméthane," Bulletin de la Société Chimique de France, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 66)
    - "Hydrogénation sous pression du tétraphénylméthane et du paraoxytétraphénylméthane," Comptes-rendus de l'Académie des Sciences, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 67)
    - "Kondensation von a-Oxy und Oxo-säuren bei kombinierter Einwirkung von Katalysatoren," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1927. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "Précipitation de l'iridium de ses solutions par l'hydrogène sous pression," Bulletin de la Société Chimique de France, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 2)
    - "Pyrogenetische Dissoziation einiger aromatischer Verbindungen unter Wasserstoff-Druck und bei kombinierter Einwirkung von Katalysatoren," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 3)
    - "Pyrogenetische Zersetzung der Ketone unter hohen Drucken," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 4)
    - "Reduktion mehrbasischer a-Oxy-säuren bei kombinierter Einwirkung von Katalysatoren," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 5)
    - "Sur l'hydrogénation de la xanthone et du xanthène," Bulletin de la Société Chimique de France, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 6)
    - "Über die Einwirkung von Methylalkohol auf Phenol bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 7)
    - "Über die katalytische Kondensation des Acetons bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken (II. Mitteilung),", Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 8)
    - "Über die Reaktion zwischen Phenol und n-Propylalkohol bei honen Temperaturen und Drucken," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 9)
    - "Über pyrogenetische Zersetzung cyclischer Ketone," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 10)
    - "Verdrängung der Metalle bezw. ihrer Oxyde aus Lösungen durch Wasserstoff unter Druck," and "Ausscheidung krystallinischer Hydroxyde des Aluminiums und Chroms aus Lösungen ihrer Salze bei hoher Temperatur unter hohem Druck," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1927. (Folder 11)
    - "Allotrope Modifikationen des Phosphores, erhalten bei hohen Temperaturen und Drucken," Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft, Negative photostat, 1928. (Folder 12)
    - "Déplacement des métaux et de leurs oxydes par l'hydrogène sous pression à des températures élevées," Chimie et industrie, Negative photostat, 1928 April. (Folder 13)
    - "Gidrirovanie solei olova pri vysokikh temperaturakh I davleniiakh," Zhurnal russkago fiziko-khimicheskago obshchestva, Negative photostat, 1928. (Folder 14)
    - "L'hydrogénation catalytique sous pression du para-oxytriphénylcarbinol et du para-oxydiphénylméthane," Bulletin de la Société chimique de France, Negative photostat, 1928. (Folder 15)